## Abhishek Sharma

https://bit.ly/abhpf

■ abhisheksharma131098@gmail.com | ■ +919852240467 +919518609407

## **EDUCATION**

# B.TECH IN ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNI-CATION ENGINEERING

2017 - 2021 | Haryana Haryana Engineering College Kurukshetra University Marks: 75.1%

## LINKS

Portfolio: bit.ly/abhpf

Github: abhisheksharma1310

in LinkedIn: abhisheksharma1310

## SKILLS

#### **PROGRAMMING**

JavaScript

#### **FRONT-END**

Html • Css • Bootstrap DOM • Jquery • ReactJs Material UI • React Suite

#### **BACK-END**

Linux • NodeJs • ExpressJs Eis • Rest APIs

#### **DATABASE**

MongoDb

#### **CLOUD**

Firebase • GCP • Azure

#### **OTHER**

Git • Figma • Canva

## **SUMMARY**

Web Developer with experience in building, debugging, testing, maintaining, and deploying web applications. My proficiency in using technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, Redux, Axios, Firebase and MongoDb, coupled with my strong problem-solving and analytical skills, make me an asset to any development team.

### **EXPERIENCE**

## **JETSONS ROBOTICS** | WEB DEVELOPER

Jan 2022 - Present | New Delhi

- Developed and maintained web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, and MongoDB database.
- Integrated and used state management libraries like Redux for data flow and state management in React web apps.
- Created REST APIs in the backend with NodeJS and ExpressJS and integrated them with frontend React web apps using Axios.
- Integrated Firebase services such as Authentication, Firestore, RTBDs, Storage, and Firebase Function to frontend as well as backend.
- Integrated Google auths in frontend for user account creation, Authentication, and authorization to the backend using JWT.
- Connected and used MongoDB database to backend server Nodejs.
- Implemented react hooks, custom hooks, UI libraries such as Material UI and React Suite, and navigation libraries such as react-router in React web apps.
- Debugged and resolved issues related to web applications.
- Conducted tests on web applications and ensured their proper functioning.
- Collaborated with the team to develop and deploy web applications.
- Implemented new features to improve the overall functionality of web apps.
- Maintained the quality of web applications by ensuring their smooth performance and user-friendliness.

#### **JETSONS ROBOTICS** | Web Developer - Intern

July 2021 – Dec 2021 | New Delhi

- Developed Frontend web apps with Reactis.
- Integrated and consumed back-end microservices, and Rest APIs on UI.
- Maintained git repositories of web development projects on GitHub and BitBucket.

## **CERTIFICATION & TRAINING**

#### **REACTJS**

INTERNSHALA - 2022 certificate: view score: 94%

#### **NODEJS**

INTERNSHALA - 2023

certificate: view score: 100%